portlandcvb.com 2011-10-07

# Privacy Policy — Travel Portland

It is Travel Portland's policy to treat any personally identifiable information submitted via our web site as strictly confidential.

Travel Portland does not make your personal information available to third parties for any reason, except to fulfill requests made by you and / or your company. However, Travel Portland may use the information you provide to inform you directly about information, products or services that may be of interest to you.

### Forms

Travel Portland employs the use of various forms for purposes including, but not limited to:

  * Event RSVPs
  * Magazine / brochure requests
  * General inquiries
  * Direct contact requests to Travel Portland staff / departments

Information submitted via such forms is stored on Travel Portland's server(s) and is not shared with third parties except as needed to fulfill your specific request. Only authorized Travel Portland staff have access to such information.

### E-newsletter subscriptions

Travel Portland maintains a variety of e-mail newsletters to provide valuable information to our partners, customers and other individuals that intentionally request such information. Users must opt in to any of our e-newsletters, and any information collected in the subscription process is kept purely confidential and is never shared with or sold to any third party.

Travel Portland works with an outside vendor in the fulfillment of our e-newsletters. Their full privacy policy is available here: <http://www.eroi.com/miscellaneous/privacy/>.

All of our e-newsletters include links in the footer of the e-mail for managing all aspects of your subscription, including the ability to globally unsubscribe from such communications.

### E-commerce

Travel Portland works with third party vendors to fulfill requests that involve financial transactions. All such transactions are transmitted in a secure fashion, utilizing SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) and any information collected is protected on secure networks. As with all information collected by Travel Portland or our transaction / fulfillment providers, your information is never shared beyond what is necessary to process your pavement and request. Some information collected during the e-commerce transaction process may be stored to make future purchases more efficient for you.

Travel Portland utilizes Authorize.Net as our secure transaction processor (with the exception of accommodations / travel bookings - see subsequent section). Authorize.Net adheres to strict industry standards for payment processing, including:

  * 128-bit Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology for secure Internet Protocol (IP) transactions.
  * Industry leading encryption hardware and software methods and security protocols to protect customer information.
  * Compliance with the Payment Card Industry (PCI) Data Security Standard.

### Accommodations and Travel Booking / Reservations

Travel Portland partners with ARES for accommodations and related travel booking and reservations transactions. All transactions are secured using the same or similar security technologies as described under the E-commerce section above.

ARES' full security and privacy policy is available here:[ http://reservations.travelportland.com/3496_privacy.html](http://reservations.travelportland.com/3496_privacy.html).

### Google Analytics

This web site uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the web site analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the web site (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the web site, compiling reports on web site activity for web site operators and providing other services relating to web site activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.
